Register to the Winifred Armstrong papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1920-1995. (Box 10-52)
  - Pan-Africanism. Notes, memoranda, reports, press releases and printed matter
    - 1958-1961 (Folder 31: 13)
    - 1962-1964 (Folder 31: 14)
  - Partnership for Productivity. Letter, 1971 (Folder 31: 15)
  - Patents. Printed article, 1968 (Folder 31: 16)
  - Phelps-Stokes Fund. Correspondence, memoranda, report, speech and study re activities in Africa, 1961-1974 (Folder 32: 1)
  - Portugal and Portuguese Africa. Notes, press releases and printed matter, 1970-1975 (Folder 32: 2)
  - Private Agencies Cooperating Together. Brochure, 1973 (Folder 32: 3)
  - Race relations (general). Notes, memoranda and printed matter, 1964-1974. (Folder 32: 4)
  - Refugees (general). Bulletins, press releases and prited matter re refugees in Africa, 1966-1972 (Folder 32: 5)
  - Roan Antelope Copper Mines (Northern Rhodesia/Zambia)
    - Personnel officers' handbook, 1956 (Folder 32: 6-7)
    - Information booklet for European employees, 1959 (Folder 32: 8)
  - Roan Consolidated Mines Limited (Zambia)
    - Annual reports, 1970-1974 (Folder 33: 1)
    - Career and information booklets, 1972 and undated (Folder 33: 2)
  - Roan Selection Trust Limited
    - Memoranda, press release and report to shareholders re Zambian government acquisition of share in ownership, 1966-1970 (Folder 33: 3)
    - Publications. Annual reports, training reports and journals
      - 1964-1967 (Folder 33: 4)
      - 1968-1969 (Folder 33: 5)
  - Rwanda. Printed matter, 1961-1973 (Folder 33: 6)
  - Scandinavian Institute of African Studies. Conference papers re refugees and brochure, 1966 (Folder 33: 7)
  - Scientists' Institute for Public Information. Bulletin, 1971 (Folder 33: 8)
  - Selection Trust Limited. Memorandum and annual reports, 1967-1973 (Folder 33: 9)
  - Senegal. Economic reports and printed matter, 1962-1973 (Folder 33: 10)
  - Sierra Leone. Correspondence, memoranda, reports and printed matter (Folder 34)
    - 1959-1968 (Folder 34: 1)
    - 1969-1995 and undated (Folder 34: 2)
  - Sociï¿½tï¿½ Internationale Financiï¿½re pour les Investissements et le Dï¿½veloppement en Afrique (SIFIDA). Correspondence, memoranda and printed matter, 1969-1970 (Folder 34: 3)
  - Somalia. Press releases, speech and printed matter, 1967-1974 (Folder 34: 4)
  - South Africa
    - General. Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, bulletins, speeches, conference papers, statements, press releases, United Nations issuances and printed matter. Includes material on apartheid issues
      - 1929-1951 (Folder 34: 5)
      - 1952-1953 (Folder 34: 6)
      - 1955 (Folder 34: 7)
      - 1956 (Folder 34: 8)
      - 1957 (Folder 34: 9)
      - 1958 (Folder 35: 1)
      - 1960-1962 (Folder 35: 2)
      - 1963-1964 (Folder 35: 3)
      - 1965 (Folder 35: 4)
      - 1966 (Folder 35: 5)
      - 1967 (Folder 35: 6)
      - 1968 (Folder 35: 7)
      - 1968 (contd.) (Folder 36: 1)
      - 1969 (Folder 36: 2)
      - 1970 (Folder 36: 3)
      - 1971 (Folder 36: 4)
      - 1972 (Folder 36: 5)
      - 1973 (Folder 37: 1)
      - 1974 (Folder 37: 2)
      - 1975-1978 (Folder 37: 3)
      - Undated (Folder 37: 4)
  - Buthelezi, Mangosuthu Gatsha (Zululand chief). Correspondence, notes, memoranda, statements, speeches and printed matter. Includes material on Buthelezi's visit to the United States in 1973
    - 1970-1972 (Folder 37: 5)
    - 1973 (Folder 37: 6-7)
    - 1974-1975 and undated (Folder 37: 8)
  - Great Britain. Parliament. House of Commons. Expenditure Committee. Trade and Industry Sub-Committee. Investigation of wages and conditions of African workers employed by British firms in South Africa
    - Minutes of evidence, 1973 (Folder 38: 1-7)
    - Fifth report, 1974 (Folder 38: 3)
  - Mangope, L. M. (Bothuphatswana chief minister). Correspondence, notes and memoranda, 1973-1974 (Folder 38: 4)
  - Mining. Printed matter
    - 1947-1958 (Folder 38: 5)
    - 1965-1978 (Folder 38: 6)
  - United States investment
    - General. Notes, memoranda, statistics, lists, studies and printed matter
      - 1956-1970 (Folder 38: 7)
      - 1971-1974 (Folder 39: 1)
    - United States. Congress. House. Committee on Foreign Affairs. Subcommittee on Africa. Hearings on U.S. business involvement in southern Africa, 1971 (Folder 39: 2)
  - University of Stellenbosch. Bureau for Economic Research. Printed reports, 1970-1971 (Folder 39: 3)
  - South African Institute of Race Relations
    - Correspondence, memoranda and conference proceedings, 1965-1973 (Folder 39: 4)
    - Publications
      - 1956-1969 (Folder 39: 5)
      - 1970-1973 (Folder 40: 1)
      - 1974 (Folder 40: 2)
  - Soviet bloc. U.S. Department of State studies, 1961 (Folder 40: 3)
  - Sudan. Correspondence, notes, memoranda and printed matter, 1962-1974 (Folder 40: 4)
  - Swaziland. Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports and printed matter
    - 1963-1969 (Folder 40: 5)
    - 1970-1974 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Taiwan. Printed matter, 1969-1974 (Folder 40: 7)
  - Tanzania (Tanganyika; Zanzibar). Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, speeches and printed matter
    - 1962-1964 (Folder 41: 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Folder 41: 2)
    - 1967 (Folder 41: 3)
    - 1968-1972 (Folder 41: 4)
    - 1973-1978 and undated (Folder 41: 5)
  - Togo. Letter, notes and printed matter, 1970-1974 (Folder 41: 6)
    - Tsumeb Corporation (Namibia). Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, board meeting materials and printed matter
    - 1964-1966 (Folder 41: 7)
    - 1967-1971 (Folder 41: 8)
    - 1972 (Folder 42: 1)
    - 1973-1974 (Folder 42: 2)
  - Uganda. Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports and printed matter, 1958-1973 (Folder 42: 3)
  - United Arab Emirates. Notes and printed matter, 1970-1972 (Folder 42: 4)
  - United Nations
    - General. Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, speeches and printed matter. Includes material relating to Africa
      - 1960-1971 (Folder 42: 5)
      - 1972 (Folder 42: 6)
      - 1973-1978 and undated (Folder 43: 1)
    - Decolonization issues. Printed matter, 1970-1977 (Folder 43: 2)
    - United States affiliated organizations. Correspondence, notes, memoranda, speeches and printed matter, 1961-1974 (Folder 43: 3)
  - United Nations. Committee on Natural Resources. Memoranda and bulletins, 1971-1974 (Folder 43: 4)
  - United Nations Conference on Trade and Development. Printed matter, 1968-1974 (Folder 43: 5)
  - United States
    - General. Reports and printed matter. Includes material re U.S. involvement in Africa
      - 1940-1964 (Folder 43: 6)
      - 1965-1977 (Folder 43: 7)
    - Economy. Printed matter, 1967-1974 (Folder 44: 1)
  - United States. Department of Commerce. Publications re economies of individual countries of Africa, 1956-1967 (Folder 44: 2)
  - United States. Department of State. Publications re U.S. policy in Africa, 1959-1973 (Folder 44: 3)
  - World Bank (International Bank for Reconstruction and Development; International Finance Corporation). Notes, memoranda, reports, speeches and printed matter
    - 1960-1972 (Folder 44: 4)
    - 1973-1974 (Folder 44: 5)
  - Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A. Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports and printed matter, mainly re YWCA involvement in Africa, 1963-1971 (Folder 44: 6)
  - Zambia (Northern Rhodesia)
    - General. Notes, memoranda, bulletins, reports, studies, speeches and printed matter
      - 1954-1957 (Folder 45: 1)
      - 1958 (Folder 45: 2)
      - 1964-1967 (Folder 45: 3)
      - 1968 (Folder 45: 4)
      - 1969 (Folder 46: 1)
      - 1970 (Folder 46: 2)
      - 1971 (Folder 46: 3)
      - 1972 (Folder 46: 4)
      - 1973 (Folder 46: 5)
      - 1974 (Folder 46: 6)
      - Undated (Folder 46: 7)
    - Chaput, Michael Joseph, "Zambian State Enterprise: The Politics and Management of Nationalized Development." Typescript doctoral dissertation, Syracuse University, 1971 (Folder 47: 1-2)
    - Economy. Correspondence, memoranda, bulletins, budget and statistical data and printed matter
      - 1964-1970 (Folder 47: 3)
      - 1971-1974 (Folder 47: 4)
    - Education and training. Reports and printed matter, 1958-1971. (Folder 48: 1)
    - Fuel. Memoranda, statistics and printed matter, 1966-1970 (Folder 48: 2)
    - Government. Notes, memoranda, bulletins, press releases, lists of officials and printed matter, 1965-1974 (Folder 48: 3)
    - History. Printed matter, 1961-1969 (Folder 48: 4)
    - Industry. Directory and prospectus, 1963-1967 (Folder 48: 5)
    - Investment. Memoranda, bulletins, reports, statistics and printed matter
      - 1962-1966 (Folder 48: 6)
      - 1967-1978 (Folder 48: 7)
    - Kafue Flats development. Speech and printed matter, 1963-1965 (Folder 49: 1)
    - Kapwepwe, Simon (vice president of Zambia). Memoranda and printed matter, 1963-1973 (Folder 49: 2)
    - Kaunda, Kenneth (president of Zambia). Correspondence, memoranda, speeches and printed matter, 1964-1973. (Folder 49: 3)
    - Labor. Correspondence, memoranda, bulletins, reports and printed matter, 1956-1974 (Folder 49: 4)
    - Mindeco Limited (Zambian government-controlled mining corporation). Speeches, annual reports and other publications, 1970-1972 (Folder 49: 5)
    - Mine training program for African workers. Memoranda, press releases and printed matter, 1958 (Folder 49: 6)
    - Mining
      - General. Correspondence, memoranda, bulletins, reports and printed matter
        - 1957-1969 (Folder 49: 7)
        - 1970-1975 (Folder 50: 1)
      - Mining industry yearbooks
        - 1965-1967 (Folder 50: 2)
        - 1968-1969 (Folder 50: 3)
        - 1972-1973 (Folder 50: 4)
    - Nationalization. Memoranda, bulletins, press releases and printed matter
      - 1966-1969 (Folder 50: 5)
      - 1970-1972 (Folder 50: 6)
      - 1973-1974 (Folder 50: 7)
    - Nchanga Consolidated Copper Mines (Zambian government-controlled mining corporation). Memoranda, annual report and printed matter, 1970-1972 (Folder 51: 1)
    - Power, Electric. Memoranda, notes, bulletins and printed matter, 1966-1974 (Folder 51: 2)
    - Prain, Sir Ronald L. (chairman, Selection Trust group). Speeches and printed articles, 1953-1973 (Folder 51: 3)
    - Profiles of personalities. Printed articles, 1963-1969 (Folder 51: 4)
    - Transportation. Notes, memoranda, bulletins, reports and printed matter. Includes material on the Tan-Zam Railway
      - 1964-1969 (Folder 51: 5)
      - 1970-1972 (Folder 51: 6)
      - 1973-1974 (Folder 51: 7)
    - United States banking loans. Notes, memoranda, reports and studies, 1972-1973 (Folder 51: 8)
    - Unity League (organization of whites in Northern Rhodesia/Zambia). Clippings, 1954 (Folder 51: 9)
  - Zimbabwe (Southern Rhodesia; Rhodesia). Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, press releases and printed matter. Includes material on the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland and on international sanctions against Rhodesia
    - 1953-1957 (Folder 51: 10)
    - 1958 (Folder 52: 1)
    - 1960-1962 (Folder 52: 2)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 52: 3)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 52: 4)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 52: 5)
    - 1974 and undated (Folder 52: 6)
  - Miscellany. Notes, memoranda and printed matter, 1959-1975 (Folder 52: 7)
- Audiovisual File, 1969-1973. (Box 52, Tape cabinet)
  - Photographs, 1969-1973. (Folder 52: 8)
  - Sound recording from National Planning Association, 1970 (Folder Tape cabinet)
- Incremental Materials (Box 53-57)